Igor Vodchits

CDMX Mexico | +52 55 8512 0921 ivodchits.ca@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/igor-vodchits-51995a161 | ivodchits.github.io/portfolio/



Summary

Highly-skilled Programmer with 7 years in Game Development who values the creative process and connections the most. Advanced knowledge of Unity game engine and C# programming language. Exceptional communication and problem-solving skills. Proficient in both slow-paced development and rapid prototyping.

Skills

- Unity
- C#
- · Game Development
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Performance Optimization

- .NET development
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Problem-Solving
- Effective Communication
- Prototyping

Work History

Senior Software Engineer

TinyWizard | Remote | September 2024 - Current

- Designed and implemented a scalable and versatile UI framework utilizing modern trends, such as addressables, asynchronous programming, and logic encapsulation.
- Coordinated with other engineers to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.
- Enhanced game performance both in gameplay and meta states.
- Built a flexible tutorial system.
- Closely collaborated with other team members via code reviews and agile development cycle.

Game Programmer

Gameloft Toronto | Toronto, Canada | May 2022 - February 2024

- Worked on multiple unannounced projects for various platforms.
- Created countless essential game systems, like 3C or tutorial framework, for different games.
- Tech stack included Unity, C#, C++, Lua and other proprietary libraries and frameworks.
- Successfully implemented uNode and Animancer tools as efficient alternative to Unity Animator, as well as Nova framework instead of Unity UI.
- Helped deliver smooth launch of Fresh Planet's game "SongPop Party" on Nintendo Switch.
- Judged students' works from technical perspective during XP summit showcase.

Unity Developer

IT Territory | Moscow, Russia | December 2021 - March 2022

- Developed mobile multiplayer auto-battler called Castle Duels.
- · Created tools for game designers and artists.
- Improved gameplay and performance.
- Developed new features.
- Ensured smooth and efficient UI animation.

Unity Developer

GD Company | Moscow, Russia | November 2020 - November 2021

- Created multiplayer top-down shooter prototype with tagging mechanics that allowed players to convert opponents into one's own team.
- That prototype later evolved into Grand Wars: Mafia City, multiplayer game featuring region captures and massive brawls with Al companion mobsters.
- Implemented countless essential and quality-of-life features, including projectiles, region capturing, tutorial, and others.
- Created efficient algorithms for Al-controlled characters to follow players and help them in combat utilizing different tactics.

Unity Developer

Lightmap | Moscow, Russian Federation | August 2018 - November 2019

- Developed client side of a mobile multiplayer first-person shooter Bitter End.
- Effectively used game development and teamwork skills to create gameplay features and tools for designers.
- Came up with performant solutions for in-game abilities, projectiles, jump pads and multiple other areas.
- Improved network state interpolation system.
- Utilized Photon knowledge to ensure stable P2P connection.
- Created a cool UI effect for the ability cards menu.

Unity Developer

Interactive Moolt | Moscow, Russian Federation | July 2017 - August 2018

- Developed the client side for a farming/city builder hybrid called "Fairy Town".
- Implemented server-side logic using Java.
- Optimized the game for WebGL and for mobile platforms.
- Came up with an algorithm for generating in-game orders and quests.
- Integrated 2D and 2D assets using both plugins and native Unity capabilities.
- Sustained network communication using WebSocket protocol.
- Learned to work effectively in a small team with short development lifecycles.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Languages



Additional Information

For me nothing can compare with the joy of shaping something into existence. I see my future in a role that would require both coding and soft skills.

My personal pet projects include many prototypes such as:

- a psychological thriller adventure game utilizing cloud and local LLM capabilities for content generation;
- a digital version of a board game Small World of Warcraft;
- an endless runner game with shooting mechanics;
- a multiplayer board game with mechanics similar to tabletop Game of Thrones;
- a twin-stick shooter with local coop and survival bits;
- an e-book reader app for Windows and Android;
- a drinking game for programmers where your goal is to write JS code that controls a robot on the arena while your opponent does the same. Each time your robot dies the game makes you drink.

On a personal note I try my best to be a decent person. I play video games, chess and guitar in my spare time. Fascinated by all the new technologies rapidly emerging in the recent years, such as Al and VR.